<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
 <title>Firefox OS Books</title>
 <description>A site to list books about Firefox OS</description>
 <link>http://firefoxosbooks.org</link>
 <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 00:01:00 +0000 </lastBuildDate>
 <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2009 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <ttl>1800</ttl>


 <item>
  <title>Quick Guide for Firefox OS Development</title>
  <description>Learn how easy and quick it is to develop applications for Firefox OS, the new mobile operating system by Mozilla. Empowered by this books practical approach you will learn thru examples how to develop apps from the beginning all the way to the distribution in the Firefox Markeplace.</description>
  <link>https://leanpub.com/quickguidefirefoxosdevelopment/</link>
  <category>book</category>
  <guid>https://leanpub.com/quickguidefirefoxosdevelopment/</guid>
 </item>

 <item>
  <title>Beginning Firefox OS HTML5 Game Programming</title>
  <description>In this book three standard game technologies are examined, compared, and contrasted: CSS Sprites, Canvas, and SVG (Scalable Vector Graphics). You will see examples using each of the three to move graphics, detect collisions, and more. Variations within Canvas and SVG are explored as well. You&#x27;ll also see examples for phone-specific technologies such as Touch, Vibration, Device Orientation, and Screen Orientation. You&#x27;ll also be shown how to upgrade your Firefox OS phone, how to use the Simulator if you don&#x27;t have a phone, and how to use the App Manager to put your apps on phones.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This book assumes you know the basics of HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript, and that you are interested in making games. Concepts and code are explained carefully along the way and newer options like CSS Sprites and SVG are covered extensively, as well as current JavaScript and HTML5 tips and tricks. In fact, except for the phone-specific chapters, you can use these techniques to make HTML5 games for other platforms. All the code is straight HTML5, CSS, SVG, and JavaScript with no libraries, no jQuery, nothing but pure code. The focus is 100% on Firefox OS games and I hope you will be inspired to create games for this fast-growing platform.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The book is written in an informal, friendly style that invites the reader to come along and explore the fun that is Firefox OS! There isn&#x27;t just one way to write a game, there are a great many, and it is hoped that this book can inform and inspire you to make your own games.</description>
  <link>http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00IZUYIGO/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00IZUYIGO&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=andregacom02-20&amp;linkId=4E2H6GAKNOAY2OXM</link>
  <category>book</category>
  <guid>http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00IZUYIGO/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00IZUYIGO&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=andregacom02-20&amp;linkId=4E2H6GAKNOAY2OXM</guid>
 </item>

 <item>
  <title>Beyond Web and Firefox OS - GAIA FROM ABOVE</title>
  <description>The book is provide an overview of the javascript written OS: FirefoxOS front end - gaia. We&#x27;d like to document and findout how mozilla and the community design and achieve this ongoing great goal. And try to learn things from their design decisions. The book help developers understand how B2G and Gaia fit together. And shows how the system startup and the app launching process.</description>
  <link>https://leanpub.com/gaiafromabove</link>
  <category>book</category>
  <guid>https://leanpub.com/gaiafromabove</guid>
 </item>

 <item>
  <title>Building Games for Firefox OS</title>
  <description>Join us in the quest for building games for Firefox OS, the new mobile operating system by Mozilla. Empowered by this books practical approach you will learn thru examples how to develop a full game from the beginning all the way to the distribution in the Firefox Markeplace.</description>
  <link>https://leanpub.com/buildinggamesforfirefoxos/</link>
  <category>book</category>
  <guid>https://leanpub.com/buildinggamesforfirefoxos/</guid>
 </item>

 <item>
  <title>Build HTML5 Games for Firefox OS</title>
  <description>I&#x27;m passionate about making HTML5 games, you can tell by looking at my various private projects with the &#x27;games&#x27; keyword inside: Enclave Games, js13kGames, Gamedev.js Weekly, HTML5 Gamedev Starter. Then there&#x27;s also Firefox OS - I&#x27;ve created some games for the platform and wrote a few articles. I&#x27;ve run through the whole process of preparing your game for the Firefox OS platform, testing the game on the actual device and pushing it to the Firefox Marketplace. So, why not write a book about it? It&#x27;s just another side project, so I have no idea when it will be finished, if ever. You can wish me luck using the social buttons above or send me a donation, if I ever create a proper button.</description>
  <link>http://firefoxos.enclavegames.com/</link>
  <category>book</category>
  <guid>http://firefoxos.enclavegames.com/</guid>
 </item>


</channel>
</rss>
